const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 10-year-old child is brought to the hospital with complaints of bloody diarrhea for the past 3 days. Examination and labs reveal an acute kidney injury along with thrombocytopenia. Upon taking history, the parents said that their child had an E. coli infection for the past few days. Which one of the following cells is most likely to be seen in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Heinz bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Bite cells","bool":false},{"option":"Tear drop cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schistocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cells","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A girl presented to the emergency with a complaint of easy bruising and petechia, which is on and off. Her brother also suffered from the same condition. The lab results of the girl showed increased bleeding and partial thromboplastin time. Which one of the following conditions was she suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 65-year-old male presents with a 2-month history of fever and weight loss. On examination, the spleen is palpable 6 cm below the left costal margin. Complete blood count (CBC) reveals leukocytes=125x10⁹/L, hemoglobin=7.0 gm/dL and platelets= 510X10³/µL . He is diagnosed with chronic myeloid leukemia. Which of the following defects is present in chronic myeloid leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"t(9:11)","bool":false},{"option":"t(9:22)","bool":true},{"option":"t(8:21)","bool":false},{"option":"t(15:17)","bool":false},{"option":"t(11:21)","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"An eye witness claims the victims death occurred about 12 hours ago. Which of the finding will confirm the statement?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in chemical constituents of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)","bool":false},{"option":"Rigor mortis present all over","bool":true},{"option":"Rise in potassium content of vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Greenish patch over caecum","bool":false},{"option":"Lividity fully developed and fixed","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A child presents with an enlarged spleen and jaundice. His laboratory findings include an increased red blood cell width, spherocytes with loss of pallor, and increased mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC). Which of the following would be a possible diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Myeloproliferative disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A child suffering from hemolytic uremic syndrome will have which one of the following finding in his peripheral blood smear?","answers":[{"option":"Tear drop RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Howell-jolly bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Aur rods","bool":false},{"option":"Target cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schistocytes","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"During the autopsy of a man, the coroner determines his age to be below sixty due to noting that a skull suture has not yet fused. Which of the following correctly identifies this particular skull suture?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous","bool":true},{"option":"Coronal","bool":false},{"option":"Lambdoid","bool":false},{"option":"Delta","bool":false},{"option":"Saggital","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 25-year-old male presents to the clinic with easy fatigability and generalized weakness. On examination he has blood pressure (BP)=110/60 mm of Hg, looks pale, and has koilonychia. His complete blood count (CBC) shows: Hb=9.7 g/dl, MCV=69 fl, MCHC=26 g/dl. What is the most likely cause of anemia in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Thalassemia major","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia minor","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A fresh victim of a road traffic accident is brought to the emergency department but lost his life on the\r\nway to the hospital. To confirm his death, the body is examined for all immediate signs of death. Which of\r\nthe following is an immediate sign of death?","answers":[{"option":"Primary relaxation","bool":true},{"option":"Rigor Mortis","bool":false},{"option":"Postmortem lividity","bool":false},{"option":"Algor mortis","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary relaxation","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"When does the pisiform bone begin to ossify?","answers":[{"option":"Between 7.5 and 10 years","bool":false},{"option":"Between 1 and 2 years","bool":false},{"option":"Between 10 and 12 years","bool":true},{"option":"Between 3 and 7 years","bool":false},{"option":"Between 5 and 6 years","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which of the following is the surest sign to determine that hanging was ante-mortem, rather than post-mortem?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperaemia of trachea and epiglottis","bool":true},{"option":"Cyanosis of face and lips","bool":false},{"option":"Ligature around the neck","bool":false},{"option":"Protruding tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of hyoid bone","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 13-year-old female presents to the outpatient department (OPD) with on and off menorrhagia, bleeding gums, and petechial rashes. Her laboratory reports show the following results; Hb= 12.5 g/dl, platelet count= 350,000/mm3, activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT)= 49s (normal: 29-40s). Which of the following could be the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":true},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic microangiopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 30-year-old man presents with a history of hematuria for 15 days. He also had an episode of gum bleed one day back. Considering idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP) as the diagnosis, which of the following is the best initial treatment of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombopoietin agonist","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":true},{"option":"Danazole","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmapheresis","bool":false},{"option":"Splenectomy","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 50-year-old female who has recently been diagnosed with hypertension presents to the clinic for a routine follow-up examination. On workup, she has abnormal values of hemoglobin (Hb) 7.4 mg/dl, MCV 84 fl, creatinine 5.4 mg/dl, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) 65 mmol/L, potassium 5.2 mEq/L, sodium 130 mEq/L, phosphorus 5.0 mEq/L, calcium 6.7 mg/dl. Which of the following is the most likely cause of decreased Hb in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"B12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Drug-induced gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency of erythropoietin","bool":true},{"option":"Folic acid deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 16-year-old boy presents to the emergency department with the complaint of swelling of the right knee joint after trivial trauma. History is significant for similar incidences over the past 4 years. Their family history is positive for a bleeding disorder. Investigations show: hemoglobin -  10 g/dL, white cell count - 5,000/uL, platelets - 200,000/uL, factor VIII - normal, prothrombin time (PT) - 16 seconds (control - 14 seconds), activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) - 48 seconds (control - 35 seconds). Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia B","bool":true},{"option":"Acquired hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":false},{"option":"Von willebrand disease","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A young female presents to the clinic with complaints of exertional dyspnea, fatigue, and diarrhea. Stool examination shows the presence of proglottids. CBC shows Hb = 8 g/dL, MCV = 110, presence of hyper-segmented neutrophils and eosinophilia. The physician is suspecting a worm infection. \r\nWhich of the following species is this patient most likely infected by?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":true},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Toxocara canis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which one of these disorders are characterized by the presence of 'smudge cells' in the peripheral smear?","answers":[{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myeloblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Myeloproliferative neoplasms","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic myeloblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 70-year-old man has experienced increasing fatigue for the past 6 months. On physical examination, he has non-tender axillary and cervical lymphadenopathy but no hepatosplenomegaly. The CBC shows hemoglobin, 9.5 g/dL; hematocrit, 28%; MCV, 90 μm3; platelet count, 120,000/mm3; and WBC count, 42,000/mm3. His peripheral blood smear shows a monotonous population of small, round, mature-looking lymphocytes. Flow cytometry shows these cells as CD19+, CD5+, CD23-, and deoxynucleotidyl transferase negative (TdT−). Cytogenetic and molecular analysis of the abnormal cells in his blood will most likely reveal which of the following alterations?","answers":[{"option":"t(9;22) leading to BCR-ABL rearrangement","bool":false},{"option":"t(14;18) leading to BCL2 overexpression","bool":false},{"option":"t(8;14) leading to c-MYC overexpression","bool":false},{"option":"Clonal rearrangement of T-cell receptor genes","bool":false},{"option":"Clonal rearrangement of immunoglobulin genes","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A male came to the outpatient department with the complaints of epistaxis and mucosal bleeding. Bleeding time is more than 5 minutes. Factor VIII and VIIIC are reduced. There is a history of similar illness in the family. What is your diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin K deﬁciency","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilia A","bool":false},{"option":"Christmas disease","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand disease","bool":true},{"option":"Liver failure","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which of the following is the process of giving preformed antibodies or vaccines to a person?","answers":[{"option":"Active immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Passive immunity","bool":true},{"option":"Humoral immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Cell-mediated immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Immunization","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which of these live attenuated vaccines is contraindicated during pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"MMR","bool":true},{"option":"Diphtheria","bool":false},{"option":"HBV","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"In postmortem examination of the body, the tattoo marks disappear from the skin. Which of the following should be examined?","answers":[{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid gland","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"For how long should the warfarin therapy be discontinued if a patient is given vitamin K?","answers":[{"option":"72 hours","bool":false},{"option":"48 hours","bool":false},{"option":"24 hours","bool":true},{"option":"12 hours","bool":false},{"option":"6 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Mycobacterium cannot be gram stained because of the presence of which substance in its cell wall?","answers":[{"option":"Lipotechoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoproteins","bool":false},{"option":"Mycolic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Techoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Polysaccharide","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A skull is found to have oval orbits, a sharp chin, an obtuse angle of the mandible, and smooth facial contours. The skull is more likely to belong to which of the following options?","answers":[{"option":"Male","bool":false},{"option":"Neonate","bool":false},{"option":"Infant","bool":false},{"option":"Elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Female","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A dead body is found with complete calcification of the third molar. Which of the following could be the age of this person before death?","answers":[{"option":"25 years","bool":true},{"option":"18 years","bool":false},{"option":"5 years","bool":false},{"option":"9 years","bool":false},{"option":"12 years","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"In what part of the body does postmortem lividity develop if the body was floating in the water?","answers":[{"option":"Face","bool":false},{"option":"Back","bool":false},{"option":"No lividity","bool":true},{"option":"Arms","bool":false},{"option":"Trunk","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of alteplase?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits coagulation factor VIII","bool":false},{"option":"Activates tissue plasminogen to plasmin","bool":true},{"option":"Causes vasodilation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of glycoprotein IIb/IIIa","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A person is brought to the emergency department with shortness of breath and syncope and is identified to have angina. Which of the following anticoagulants should be given to the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Enoxaparin","bool":true},{"option":"Idarucizumab","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Alteplase","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most potent thrombolytic agent but causes an increased epitope presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Reteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Alteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":true},{"option":"Tenecteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Urokinase","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 45-year-old female with chronic hypertension presents to the outpatient\r\ndepartment with petechial rashes. Laboratory shows platelet counts of 50,000. The prothrombin time (PT) and partial thromboplastin time (PTT) are both in a normal range. However, the bleeding time is elevated. Which of the following is the cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Hemolytic uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow suppression","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient department with painless lymphadenopathy in the neck and axilla. He also reports experiencing night sweats, and unexplained weight loss for the past few weeks. On physical examination, the nodes are firm and non-tender. There is no evidence of hepatosplenomegaly. The lymph nodes are of different sizes. Which of the following can be a likely cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic myeloid leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkins lymphoma","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A newborn feeds on cow milk 5 times a day. Which of the following can develop jaundice and pallor in this baby?","answers":[{"option":"Antibodies against cow milk","bool":true},{"option":"Low bioavailability","bool":false},{"option":"Low iron content","bool":false},{"option":"Low folic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Low absorption of milk","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"Which of the following worm infestations cause severe anemia during pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Pinworms","bool":false},{"option":"Tapeworms","bool":false},{"option":"Hookworms","bool":true},{"option":"Ascariasis","bool":false},{"option":"Schistosoma infection","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 7-year-old boy develops jaundice and severe anemia after consuming fava beans. Which of the following is the cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Polycythemia vera","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"G6PD deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Sickel cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 25-year-old female is transfused blood. After two weeks, she presents to the outpatient department for a follow-up with anemia, fever, and chills. Her direct Coombs test is positive. Which of the following is the cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Acute hemolytic reaction to minor groups","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed reaction to minor groups","bool":true},{"option":"Acute hemolytic reaction due to Rh group","bool":false},{"option":"Graft versus host disease","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed hemolytic reaction due to ABO blood group","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A child presented in the outpatient department for a follow-up of his CBC report. His reports are as follows: hemoglobin = 4 g/dL, MCV = 49 fl. TLC and platelets were within the normal range. What is the next best investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Repeat CBC","bool":false},{"option":"Hb electrophoresis","bool":false},{"option":"Iron profile","bool":true},{"option":"Serum vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Coombs test","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A 31-year-old male presented to the outpatient department (OPD) with complaints of jaundice. On taking a detailed history it was found he is on anti-malarial drugs. What is the most likely cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"G6PD","bool":true},{"option":"Autoimmune hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute liver failure","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"What is the best test for disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased PT and PTT","bool":false},{"option":"Increased coagulation factors","bool":false},{"option":"D-dimer","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen and FDP","bool":true},{"option":"International normalized ratio (INR)","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2023","question":"A child presented in the clinic with abdominal pain. His serum complement levels were normal. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Henoch-Schönlein purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Cryoglobulinemia","bool":false},{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr